NIRAJ CHAVAN

UI / Web Developer

Email - nirajd327@gmail.com **Phone** - +91 96071 95436

7th Heaven, B-404, B Wing, Sr. No. – 6, Hissa No. – 3, D. N. Parande Park, Dhanori, Pune - 411015

Portfolio - https://niraj-chavan.herokuapp.com/

Linkedin - https://in.linkedin.com/in/niraj-chavan-8267bb98

Career Summary

UI Developer with 6.9 years of experience in designing, developing, and managing complex e-commerce sites.

An energetic and imaginative young Web Developer who is able to work alongside other talented IT professionals in creating websites to the very highest standards.

Skilled in developing and achieving technical objectives and goals to support the organization vision while managing & developing projects of web application.

Experience – (6.9 Years)

UI DEVELOPER, SCHLUMBERGER

Sept 2019 – Present, Location – Pune

Help to integrate Wijmo in angular component with engineering team. Build reusable libraries and code for future use. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability. Reviewing requirements and design to build new UI features.

SENIOR UI ENGINEER, XPANXION INTERNATIONAL PVT. LTD.

Jan 2017 - Sept 2019, Location - Pune

Implementation of angular custom reusable components, JWT token implementation, performance optimization and API integration.

UI DEVELOPER, CONNECT | 91 WEB SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD.

(Currently known as Polyscripts Infotech Pvt. Ltd.)
Dec 2015 - Jan 2017, Location – Pune
UI enhancement designs for better user
experience, convert PSD into HTML and make the
websites compatible with all browsers.

WEB DEVELOPER, WHITECODE IT SOLUTION

July 2014 - Dec 2015, Location – Pune
Responsible for participating in the full life cycle of new website development and maintaining best practice procedures in all areas of work.

Technical Strength

HTML5, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap 4/5, JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript, Angular 2/5/7, ReactJS, Express JS, Node JS, GraphQL, JSON, WordPress, Python, Flask, SVN, GIT, MySQL, MongoDB, Jira, Rally, Microsoft Azure, Webpack, Karma, Jasmine, Jest

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 07-August-1992 Marital Status: Unmarried

Nationality: Indian

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Marathi

Education

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (COMPUTER ENGG.)

Dr. D. Y. Patil Institute of Engineering & Technology, Pune University July 2011 – June 2014

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Y. B. Patil Polytechnic, Pune (Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education) July 2008 – May 2011

SECONDRY SCHOOL EDUCATION

Sharada Vidyamandir, Maharashtra Board June 2007 – July 2008

Projects

FIELD LOGISTIC MODULE – Participate in all aspects of product development, from requirement analysis to product release. To analyse and debug the application to find a solution for incidents. Design and develop user interface using angular best practices. To integrate Wijmo Flexgrid components into FLM application. Optimize performance of the application. Responsible for ownership of the application code base which includes maintaining the integrity of the code, defining/enforcing standards and best practices, performing and participating in code reviews.

Skills – Angular 7, Wijmo Flexgrid, MongoDB, Microsoft Azure, JavaScript, Typescript, Flux Architecture, Git

Team Size – 10 **Role** – UI Developer

E-COM SHOPPING APP – An online website for e-Commerce shopping build on React JS, Express JS, Node JS and mongo DB. Creating website layout/user interfaces by using HTML/CSS technologies with responsive and flexible UI. Build back end flow and architecture. Writing code using best practices. Build admin panel for multiple roles with sets of permissions. Build architectural design of product. Design, develop and deploy modules of product. Apply deep understanding of JavaScript and React JS to build reusable UI components in a multi-device, modern web UI framework.

Skills – React JS, Node JS, Mongo DB, Express JS, Git, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4

Team Size – 2 **Role** – UI Developer

K7 SECURITY – To build dashboard for end customers to manage multiple devices from online website account. Develop software solutions using industry best practices and in the area of security and performance in a web and architecture environment. Collaborates with team and business owners in the design and analysis phases as part of self-organizing feature teams. Maintain source-code repository, participate in Code Reviews, and conduct design reviews. Participate in deployment of code into production.

Skills – Angular 7, HTML 5, SCSS, Bootstrap, JHipster, JavaScript, Typescript, Git, Rally

Team Size – 8 **Role** – UI Developer

SCOPERETAIL – Design and developed UI Interface with optimized solution for E-commerce retail product. To create custom angular 5 components for Internal framework. To create UI mock-ups, wire frames and responsive design using HTML 5, Bootstrap 4 and JavaScript. Best solutions for performance optimization techniques and unit testing strategy. Build deployment strategy and micro web-based service architecture. Integrated web rest API with front end application. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability.

Skills – Angular 7, HTML 5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, Typescript, Git, Jira, Jasmine, Karma

Team Size – 22 **Role –** UI Developer

CERTASLIM – Design and develop high performance web applications using Front-end technologies. Use mark-up languages like HTML to create user-friendly web pages. Develop new user-facing features. Build reusable code and libraries for future use. Create quality mock-ups and prototypes. Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability. Work closely with juniors and provide strong code reviews and feedback. Continually evaluate emerging frameworks and technologies to identify opportunities, trends and best practices that strengthen the development team.

Skills – Angular, HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap 3, jQuery, JavaScript, Git, Zoho

Team Size – 6 **Role** – UI Developer